<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>community | AfricaR</title>
    <link>/tag/community/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>community</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>community</title>
      <link>/tag/community/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an R community in Africa</title>
      <link>/post/lornar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/lornar/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;r-in-africa&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;R in Africa&lt;/h1&gt;
Over the past 2 years, we have seen R transform from just an academic and health care research language to one of the major languages in the budding data science community in Africa. For a long time, data scientists and related disciplines have relied on R and many other packages to analyse data, however, the broader developer community didn’t fully understand its power in the tech industry. An effective model to enter the Africa developer ecosystem relies on a small group of enthusiasts creating a safe learning environment, documenting and sharing their learning experiences and slowly attracting interested learners. Africa R users group are using this model to introduce R as a language for data science by organising communities across different cities in Africa.
&lt;style&gt;
body {text-align: justify}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;evolution-of-chapters-and-representation&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Evolution of chapters and representation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growth of technical talent in Africa positively correlates with the growth of communities around certain technologies/tools/languages. These communities are creating a long table to share opportunities on the continent. Seeing useRs evolve from just being groups of academic researchers completing their PhD or master’s degrees to attracting groups of people using R at their workplaces or for their freelance projects has given us confidence that R is part of the future of data science on the continent. When we direct the spotlight on chapters of useRs meeting up every other weekend across Africa, there is a theme of diversity that can easily
go unnoticed. This unique representation in the Africa R community shows how the useRs have created a safe space for equal active participation. Global communities like R Ladies and Women in Machine Learning and Data Science have put so many women in the community at a great centre stage of starting R user groups in their localities. The support from these groups has contributed to the early success of R user groups as the safest places to start your data science career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;our-future&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Our future&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R as a statistical programming language has a great value to the data science community on the continent and it is our role as useRs to show this value in our work, research and education. Our focus is on developing material that shows the amazing facets of R and renders it as an option on the table for potential clients and the community. R has been around for a quarter century and we are starting to see it cross paths with other programming languages thus raising a need to
create room for it in learning and early career choices. AfricaR is shining the light on R to build communities, mentor talent and power businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A newbie in the KampalR community</title>
      <link>/post/kamplr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/kamplr/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;It’s been 2 years 3 months since I have been affiliated with the Kampala R User Group aka &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kampalR?s=17&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@KampalR&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;how-it-all-started&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How it all started&lt;/h1&gt;
Alas January, everyone is excited about the new year, resolutions flying East, West and everyone eager and anticipating a year of greatness. For some of us, especially when you have been over a year out of campus and into the real world, it’s a time to reflect and rethink what direction you want your life to take.
January 2018 was that turning point for me, I loved the course I pursued at the university however I found myself in communications &amp;amp; marketing, a completely different field from what I had ever envisioned I would be doing and so so far away from my passion and what I really wanted to get my hands on.
That year I purposed to go back to my first love i.e computers and everything that comes along with it. That’s when the data science wave started sounding and sweeping over Uganda and after doing all the online research, I told myself this is it.
So the journey begins,
&lt;style&gt;
body {text-align: justify}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;kampalr&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;KampalR&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geared up, full tank I knew what I wanted so the next step was to find all the resources imaginable and start learning because over 2 years in communications had me on a totally new direction.
Checking up for meet-ups around the city and then I come across R user group, I didn’t have the slightest idea what R was, in fact to make myself feel better I imagined it was someone trying to fancy up a name for their meet-up.
Either way I registered because guess what the description had an &lt;strong&gt;Introduction to data science&lt;/strong&gt; and that’s what I wanted.
Walking into this room, I was the only lady in a room full of gentlemen and of course egos were flying, heads turning at this lady but I still sat (after-all it’s what I wanted, had to find a way to fit in).
That weekend, we had a lady facilitator which was cool of course and after the session, there was a bottle of soda and pizza. My mind was fully made up to return (partly persuaded by the pizza but also the session and the community).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joining KampalR community has been one of the best decisions I made to jumpstart my data science
career because despite the fact that I was the only lady for about 2 meet-ups before another lady
stumbled in: Her Excellency Ms Shakyrah (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cynthia_kyra?s=17&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@cynthia_kyra&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), I didn’t feel left out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community oozes inclusion, energy, passion and a deep desire to groom some of the best R users in the country. The people make it more perfect because each person in the community goes an extra mile so that their neighbour learns and also make sure no one is left behind.
The facilitators include everyone as much as possible and make the process to learn R as simple as possible.
It’s been 2 years since I joined the kampalR community, and I have not only learned R but also joined the force that makes this community meet-ups happen every month alongside &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/okello_mark?s=17&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@okello_mark&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as the lead and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cynthia_kyra?s=17&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@cynthia_kyra&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as a co-lead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have meet-ups organised at-least every month and always come up with interesting sessions to grow the community.
We have a slack channel &lt;a href=&#34;http://kampalr.slack.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;KampalR slack group&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; where we discuss all things R and also communicate about events happening.
We have also introduced study jams where you can start from the basics all the way to your first R project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KampalR is open to everyone that is interested in growing their data science journey and learning R. Novice, intermediate, expert it doesn’t matter what level you are at, join the community and let’s grow together.
We also have the ladies group &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rladieskampala?s=17&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@Rladieskampala&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; where we can start our discussions with the latest hair style and plot the coolest graphs in R.
Want to learn more about the community and more stories from the community, follow me &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/nlimilimi&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@nlimilimi&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kampalR&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@KampalR&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to get the latest in the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
